{"test_questions": [[{"question": "In a flash analog-to-digital converter, the output of each comparator is connected to an input of a ________.", "opta": "decoder", "optb": "priority encoder", "optc": "multiplexer", "optd": "demultiplexer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which term applies to the maintaining of a given signal level until the next sampling?", "opta": "Holding", "optb": "Aliasing", "optc": "Shannon frequency sampling", "optd": "\"Stair-stepping\"", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An op-amp has very ________.", "opta": "high voltage gain", "optb": "high input impedance", "optc": "low output impedance", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a 4-bit DAC, the least significant bit (LSB) is ________.", "opta": "6.25% of full scale", "optb": "0.625% of full scale", "optc": "12% of full scale", "optd": "1.2% of full scale", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The dual-slope analog-to-digital converter finds extensive use in ________.", "opta": "digital voltmeters", "optb": "function generators", "optc": "frequency counters", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ADC0804 is an example of a ________.", "opta": "single-slope analog-to-digital converter", "optb": "dual-slope analog-to-digital converter", "optc": "digital-ramp analog-to-digital converter", "optd": "successive-approximation analog-to-digital converter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a digital representation of voltages using an 8-bit binary code, how many values can be defined?", "opta": "16", "optb": "64", "optc": "128", "optd": "256", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-bit R/2R ladder digital-to-analog converter uses ________.", "opta": "one resistor value", "optb": "two resistor values", "optc": "three resistor values", "optd": "four resistor values", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary-weighted-input digital-to-analog converter has a feedback resistor, Rf, of 12 k. If 50 A of current is through the resistor, voltage out of the circuit is ________.", "opta": "0.6 V", "optb": "\u20130.6 V", "optc": "0.1 V", "optd": "\u20130.1 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The resolution of a 6-bit DAC is ________.", "opta": "63%", "optb": "64%", "optc": "15.9%", "optd": "1.59%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of ADC quantizes the analog signal into a stream of bits whose amount corresponds to the signal level?", "opta": "Successive approximation", "optb": "Sigma-delta", "optc": "Dual-slope", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary-weighted-input digital-to-analog converter has an input resistor of 100 k. If the resistor is connected to a 5 V source, current through the resistor is ________.", "opta": "50 mA", "optb": "50 A", "optc": "5 mA", "optd": "500 A", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In troubleshooting a DAC, we check its performance characteristics, such as ________.", "opta": "nonmonotonicity", "optb": "differential nonlinearity", "optc": "low and high gain", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a digital reproduction of an analog curve, accuracy can be increased by ________.", "opta": "sampling the curve more often", "optb": "sampling the curve less often", "optc": "decreasing the number of bits used to represent each sampled value", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a 4-bit R/2R ladder digital-to-analog converter, because of negative feedback, the operational amplifier keeps the inverting (minus) input near ________.", "opta": "5 volts", "optb": "zero volts", "optc": "a voltage determined by the binary weighted input", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the result of taking more samples during the quantization process?", "opta": "More errors in the analog-to-digital conversion", "optb": "More bit requirements", "optc": "More accurate signal representation", "optd": "More bit requirements and more accurate signal representation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which A/D conversion method has a fixed conversion time?", "opta": "Single-slope analog-to-digital converter", "optb": "Dual-slope analog-to-digital converter", "optc": "Digital-ramp analog-to-digital converter", "optd": "Successive-approximation analog-to-digital converter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is a typical application of digital signal processing?", "opta": "Noise elimination", "optb": "Music signal processing", "optc": "Image processing", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a DAC has a full-scale, or maximum, output of 12 V and accuracy of 0.1%, then the maximum error for any output voltage is ________.", "opta": "12 V", "optb": "120 mV", "optc": "12 mV", "optd": "0 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do we call the manipulation of an analog signal in a digital domain?", "opta": "Analog-to-digital conversion", "optb": "Digital-to-analog conversion", "optc": "Digital signal processing", "optd": "Signal filtering", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How are unwanted frequencies removed prior to digital conversion?", "opta": "Pre-filters", "optb": "Digital signal processing", "optc": "Sample-and-hold circuits", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of programming is typically used for digital signal processors?", "opta": "Assembly language", "optb": "Machine language", "optc": "C", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following best defines Nyquist frequency?", "opta": "The frequency of resonance for the filtering circuit", "optb": "The second harmonic", "optc": "The lower frequency limit of sampling", "optd": "The highest frequency component of a given analog signal", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an A/D conversion error?", "opta": "Differential nonlinearity", "optb": "Missing code", "optc": "Incorrect code", "optd": "Offset", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Settling time is normally defined as the time it takes a DAC to settle within ________.", "opta": "1/8 LSB of its final value when a change occurs in the input code", "optb": "1/4 LSB of its final value when a change occurs in the input code", "optc": "1/2 LSB of its final value when a change occurs in the input code", "optd": "1 LSB of its final value when a change occurs in the input code", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}